So today, we're going to give
an instructor-led lecture,
talking about some key topics
in Transformers and LLMs
these days.
In particular, we'll be
talking about agents,
and I'll be discussing
Emergent Abilities,
Intermediate-Guided
reasoning, as well as BabyLM.
So let me actually go to my part
because Div is not here yet.
So I'm sure many
of you have read
this paper, Emergent Abilities
of Large Language Models,
from 2022.
So I'll briefly go
through some of them.
So basically, an
ability is emergent
if it is present and larger,
but not smaller models.
And it would not have
been directly predicted
by extrapolating performance
from smaller models.
So you can think of performance.
It's basically near-random
until a certain threshold,
called a critical threshold.
And then it improves
very heavily.
This is known as a
phase transition.
And again, it would not have
been extrapolated or predicted
if you were to extend the curve
of the performance of smaller
models.
It's more of a jump,
which we'll see later.
So here's an example
of few-shot prompting
for many different tasks.
For example, modular
arithmetic, unscrambling words,
different tasks and so forth.
And you'll see that
performance jumps very heavily
up until a certain point.
I believe the x-axis
here is the number
of training flops, which
correspond to basically model
scale.
So you'll see in many cases
around 10 to the 22 or 10
to the 23 training flops.
There's a massive
exponential jump or increase
in terms of model performance
on these tasks, which was not
present on smaller scales.
So it's quite unpredictable.
And here are some examples
of this occurring using
augmented prompting strategies.
So I'll be talking a bit
later about chain of thought.
But basically, these
strategies improve
the ability of getting behavior
from models on different tasks.
So you see, for example, with
Chain-of-Thought Reasoning,
that's an emergent behavior
that happens again around 10
to the 22 training flops.
And without it, model
performance on GSM8K,
which is a
mathematics benchmark,
it doesn't really improve
heavily, but chain of thought
leads to that emergent
behavior or sudden increase
in performance.
And here's just a table
from the paper, which
has a bigger list of
emergent abilities of LLMs,
as well as their scale
at which they occur.
So I recommend
that you check out
the paper to learn a bit more.
And so one thing
researchers have
been wondering is, why does
this emergence occur exactly?
And even now, there's
few explanations
for why that happens.
And the authors also found that
the evaluation metrics used
to measure these
abilities may not fully
explain why they emerge.
And they suggest some
alternative evaluation metrics,
which I encourage you to
read more in the paper.
So other than scaling
up, to encourage
these emergent abilities,
which could endow
even larger LMs with further
new emergent abilities,
what else can be done?
Well, things like investigating
new architectures,
higher quality data, which is
very important for performance
on all tasks, improved
training and improved training
procedures, could enable
emergent abilities
to occur, especially on
smaller models, which
is a current growing area
of research, which I'll also
talk about a bit more later.
Other abilities
include potentially
improving the few-shot
prompting abilities
of LMs, theoretical and
interpretability research
again, to try to understand why
emergent abilities is a thing
and how we can maybe
leverage that further,
as well as maybe some
computational linguistics work.
So with these large models
and emergent abilities,
there's also risks.
There's potential
societal risks.
For example, truthfulness,
bias, and toxicity risks,
as emergent abilities
incentivizes further scaling
up language models, for example,
up to GPT-4 size or further.
However, this may lead to
bias increasing, as well as
toxicity and the memorization
of training data.
That's one thing that
these larger models are
more potent at, and
there's potential risks
in future language
models that have
also not been discovered yet.
So it's important that we
approach this in a safe manner
as well.
And, of course, emergent
abilities and larger models
have also led to
sociological changes,
changes in the community's
views, and use of these models.
Most importantly, it's
led to the development
of general-purpose
models, which perform
on a wide range of tasks,
not just particular tasks
it was trained for.
For example, when you
think of ChatGPT, GPT-3.5,
as well as GPT-4, they are
more general-purpose models,
which work well
across the board,
and can then be further
adapted to different use cases,
mainly through in-context
prompting and so forth.
This has also led to new
applications of language models
outside of NLP.
For example, they're
being used a lot now
for text-to-image generation.
The encoder part of those
text-to-image models
are basically transformer
models or large language models,
as well as things like
robotics and so forth.
So you'll know that--
earlier this quarter,
Jim Phang gave
a talk about how they're using
GPT-4 and so forth in Minecraft
and for robotics work, as well
as long-range horizon tasks
for robotics.
And yeah.
So basically, in
general, it's led
to a shift in the NLP community
towards general purpose rather
than task-specific models.
And as of stated earlier, some
directions for future work
include model scaling,
further model scaling.
Although, I believe that we
will soon probably be reaching
a limit or point of diminishing
returns with just more model
scale, improved model
architectures and training
methods, data scaling.
So I also believe that data
quality is of high importance,
possibly even more
important than the model
scale and the model itself,
better techniques for
and understanding of
prompting, as well as exploring
and enabling performance
on frontier tasks
that current models are not
able to perform well on.
So GPT-4 pushed
the limit of this.
It's able to perform
well on many more tasks,
but studies have
shown that it still
suffers from even some more
basic reasoning, analogical,
and common-sense reasoning.
So I just had some
questions here.
I'm not sure how much
time we have to address.
So for the first
one, like I said,
emergent abilities, I think,
will arise to a certain point,
but there will be a limit or
point of diminishing returns
as model scale, as
well as data scale
rises, because I
believe at some point,
there will be overfitting.
And there's only so
much you can learn
from all the data on the web.
So I believe that more
creative approaches
will be necessary after a
certain point, which also
addresses the second question.
So I will move on.
If anybody has any
questions, also,
feel free to
interrupt at any time.
So the second thing
I'll be talking about
is this thing called
Intermediate-Guided Reasoning.
So I don't think this
is actually a term.
It's typically called
Chain-of-Thought Reasoning,
but it's not just--
chains are now being used.
So I wanted to give
it a more broad title.
So I called it
Intermediate-Guided Reasoning.
So this was inspired
by this work
also by my friend, Jason,
who was at Google now
at OpenAI, called
Chain-of-Thought Reasoning
or CoT.
This is basically a series of
intermediate reasoning steps,
which has been shown to
improve LLM performance,
especially on more
complex reasoning tasks.
It's inspired by
the human thought
process, which is to
decompose many problems
into multi-step problems.
For example, when you
answer an exam, when
you're solving math
questions on an exam,
you don't just go
to the final answer.
You write out your steps.
Even when you're just
thinking through things,
you break it down into a
piece-wise or step-by-step
fashion, which allows
you to typically arrive
at a more accurate final
answer and more easily arrive
at the final answer
in the first place.
Another advantage is this
provides an interpretable window
into the behavior of the model.
You can see exactly how
it arrived at an answer.
And if it did so
incorrectly, where
in its reasoning path that
it goes wrong or starts
going down an incorrect path
of reasoning, basically?
And it basically
exploits the fact
that deep down in
the model's weights,
it knows more about
the problem than simply
prompting it to get a response.
So here's an example
where on the left side,
you can see the
standard prompting.
You ask it a math question,
and it just simply
gives you an answer.
Whereas on the
right, you actually
break it down step by step.
You get it to show it steps
to solve the mathematical word
problem step by step.
And you'll see here that it
actually gets the right answer
unlike standard prompting.
So there's many different ways
we can potentially improve
Chain-of-Thought Reasoning.
In particular, it's also
an emergent behavior
that results in performance
gains for larger language
models.
But still, even
in larger models,
there's still a non-negligible
fraction of errors.
These come from calculator
errors, symbol mapping errors,
one missing step
errors, as well as
bigger errors due to larger
semantic understanding
issues and generally
incoherent chains of thought.
And we can potentially
investigate
methods to address these.
So as I said,
Chain-of-Thought mainly
works for huge models
of approximately 100
billion parameters or more.
And there's three
potential reasons
they do not work very
well for smaller models.
And that smaller models
are fundamentally
more limited and incapable.
They fail at even relatively
easier symbol mapping tasks,
as well as arithmetic tasks.
They inherently are able to
do math less effectively.
And they often have
logical loopholes
and just never arrive
at a final answer.
For example, it goes on and on.
It's like an infinite
loop of logic that never
actually converges anywhere.
So if we're able to potentially
improve Chain-of-Thought
for smaller models, this could
provide significant value
to the research community.
Another thing is to
potentially generalize it.
Right now, Chain-of-Thought
has a more rigid definition
and format.
It's very step-by-step,
very concrete and defined.
As a result, its advantages are
for particular domains and types
of questions.
For example, the task usually
must be challenging and require
multi-step reasoning, and
it typically works better
for things like
arithmetic, and not
so much for things like response
generation, QA and so forth.
And furthermore, it works
better for problems or tasks
that have a relatively
flat scaling curve.
Whereas when you
think of humans,
we think through different
types of problems in multiple
different ways, our quote,
unquote "scratchpad"
that we use to think about
and arrive at a final answer
for a problem.
It's more flexible and
open to different reasoning
structures compared to such
a rigid step-by-step format.
So hence, we can maybe
potentially generalize
Chain-of-Thought
to be more flexible
and work for more
types of problems.
So now, I'll briefly discuss
some alternative or extension
works to Chain-of-Thought.
One is called Tree of Thought.
This basically is
more like a tree,
which considers multiple
different reasoning paths.
It also has the ability to look
ahead and backtrack, and then
go on other areas or other
branches of the tree,
as necessary.
So this leads to
more flexibility,
and it's shown to improve
performance on different tasks,
including arithmetic tasks.
There's also this work
by my friend called
Socratic Questioning,
and it's sort
of a divide-and-conquer
fashion algorithm simulating
the recursive thinking
process of humans.
So it uses a large-scale
language model
to propose subproblems,
given a more complicated
original problem.
And just like Tree
of Thought, it also
has recursive
backtracking and so forth.
And the purpose is to
answer all the subproblems
and go in an upwards fashion
to arrive at a final answer
to the original problem.
There's also this line of
work, which actually uses code,
as well as programs to help
arrive at a final answer.
For example, Program-Aided
Language Models.
It generates intermediate
reasoning steps
in the form of code, which is
then offloaded to a runtime,
such as a Python interpreter.
And the point here is to
decompose the natural language
problem into runnable steps.
So hence, the amount of work
for the large language model
is lower.
Its purpose now
is simply to learn
how to decompose
the natural language
problem into those
runnable steps,
and these steps themselves
are then fed to, for example,
a Python interpreter
in order to solve them.
And Program-of-Thought
here, PoT,
is very similar to this, and
that it breaks it down into step
by step of code instead
of natural language,
which is then executed
by an actual code
interpreter or program.
So this, again, works
well for many tasks that--
for example, things like
arithmetic, as you see that.
Those are both of the examples
for both of these papers.
And just like what
I said earlier,
these also do not work
very well for things
like response generation,
open-ended question answering
and so forth.
And there's other work, for
example, Faith and Fate.
This actually
breaks down problems
into substeps in the form
of computation graphs, which
they show also works well
for things like arithmetic.
So you see that
there's a trend here
of this intermediate-guided
reasoning working
very well for mathematical,
as well as logical problems,
but not so much
for other things.
So again, I encourage you
guys to maybe check out
the original papers if
you want to learn more.
There's a lot of interesting
work in this area these days.
And I'll also be posting these
slides, as well as sending them.
We'll probably post them on the
website, as well as Discord,
but I'll also send them
through an email later.
So very lastly, I want to
touch upon this thing called
the BabyLM Challenge
or Baby Language Model.
So like I said earlier,
I think, at some point,
scale will reach a point
of diminishing returns,
as well as the fact
that further scale comes
with many challenges.
For example, it takes a long
time and costs a lot of money
to train these big models,
and they cannot really be used
by individuals who are not at
huge companies with hundreds
or thousands of GPUs
and millions of dollars.
So there's this challenge
called BabyLM or Baby Language
Model, which is
attempting to train
language models,
particularly smaller ones,
on the same amount of linguistic
data available to a child.
So data sets have grown by
orders of magnitude, as well
as, of course, model size.
For example, Chinchilla sees
approximately 1.4 trillion words
during training.
This is around 10,000 words
for every one word that
a 13-year-old child, on average,
has heard as they grow up
or develop.
So the purpose here is,
can we close this gap?
Can we train smaller models
on lower amounts of data
while hopefully still attempting
to get the performance
of these much larger models?
So basically, we're
trying to focus
on optimizing pre-training,
given data limitations inspired
by human development.
And this will also
ensure that research
is possible for more
individuals, as well as labs,
and potentially possible
on a university budget,
as it seems now that
a lot of research
is restricted to
large companies, which
I said have a lot of
resources, as well as money.
So again, why BabyLM?
Well, it can greatly
improve the efficiency
of training, as well as
using larger language models.
It can potentially open up new
doors and potential use cases.
It can lead to improved
interpretability,
as well as alignment.
Smaller models will be
easier to control, align,
as well as interpret
what exactly is going on,
compared to incredibly large
LLMs, which are basically
huge black boxes.
This will, again,
potentially lead
to enhanced open-source
availability.
For example, large language
models runnable on consumer PCs,
as well as by smaller
labs and companies.
The techniques discovered
here can also possibly
be applied to larger scales.
And further, this may lead
to greater understanding
of the cognitive
models of humans
and how exactly we are able
to learn language much more
efficiently than these
large language models.
So there may be a flow of
knowledge from cognitive science
and psychology to NLP
and machine learning,
but also in the other direction.
So briefly, the
BabyLM training data
that the authors of
this challenge provide,
it's a developmentally-inspired
pre-training data set,
which has under 100 million
words, because children
are exposed to approximately
2 to 7 million words per year
as they grow up, up
to the age of 13.
That's approximately
90 million words.
So they round up to 100.
It's mostly transcribed speech,
and their motivation there
is that most of the input
to children is spoken.
And thus, their data set
focuses on transcribed speech.
It's also mixed domain
because children are typically
exposed to a variety
of language or speech
from different domains.
So it has child-directed
speech, OpenSubtitles,
which are subtitles
of movies, TV shows
and so forth, simple
children's books
which contain stories
that children would likely
hear as they're growing up.
But it also has some Wikipedia,
as well as Simple Wikipedia.
And here are just some examples
of child-directed speech,
children's stories,
Wikipedia and so forth.
So that's it for my portion
of the presentation.
And I'll hand it off to Div, who
will talk a bit about AI agents.
Thanks.
Yeah.
So everyone must have seen--
there's this new trend
where everything is
transitioning to more agents.
That's the new hot thing.
And we're seeing this--
people are going more
from language models
to now building AI agents.
And then what's the
biggest difference?
Why agents?
Why just not train a big
large language model?
And I was sort of like go into
why, what's the difference?
And then, also, discuss a
bunch of things such as,
how can you use agents
for taking actions?
What are some emergent
architectures?
How can you build
human-like agents?
How can you use it for
computer interactions?
How do you solve problems
for long-term memory
and personalization?
And there's a lot
of other things
you can do with
multi-agent communication.
And there are some
future directions.
So I'll try to cover
as much as I can.
So first, let's talk about why
should we even build AI agents.
There's a key thesis, which is
that humans will communicate
with AI using natural language.
And AI will be operating
all the machines,
thus allowing for more intuitive
and efficient operations.
So right now, what happens
is, me, as a human,
I'm directly using my
computer I'm using my phone,
but this is really inefficient.
We are not optimized by
nature to be able to do that.
We are actually really,
really bad at this.
But if you can just talk to our
AI, just like with language,
and the AI is just really good
enough that it can just do this
super faster, obviously like
100x speeds compared to human,
and that's going to happen.
And I think that's
the future of how
things are going to evolve
in the next five years.
And I call this Software 3.0.
I have a blog post
about this that you
can read if you want
to, where the idea is
you can think of a
large language model
as a computing chip in a sense.
So it's similar to a chip
that's powering a whole system.
And then you can build
abstractions and all.
Cool.
So why do we need agents?
So usually, a single call
to a large language model
is not enough.
You need chaining.
You need recursion.
You need a lot of more things.
And that's where we want to
build systems, not just like
a single monolith.
Second is, yeah, so
how do we do this?
So we do a lot of techniques,
especially around multiple calls
to a model.
And there's a lot of
ingredients involved here.
And I will say,
building an agent is
very similar to maybe thinking
about building a computer.
So the LLM is like a CPU.
So you have a CPU.
But now you want to
solve the problems.
How do you put ram?
How do you put memory?
How do you do actions?
How do you build an interface?
How do you add internet access?
How do you personalize
it to the user?
So this is almost like you are
trying to build a computer.
And that's what makes it
a really hard problem.
And this is like an example of a
general architecture for agents.
This is from Lilian Weng,
who's a researcher at OpenAI.
And you can imagine, an agent
has a lot of ingredients.
So you want to
have memory, which
would be short-term, long-term.
You have tools,
which could be like,
you can go and use
classical tools
like a Calculator, Calendar,
Code Interpreter, et cetera.
You want to have some sort
of like planning layer, where
you can have Chain-of-Thoughts
and Trees of Thoughts,
as Steven discussed,
and use all of that
to actually act on behalf of
a user in some environment.
We'll go maybe discuss MULTION
a bit, just to give a sense.
Also, the talk won't
be focused on that.
So this is an agent
I'm building, which
is more of a browser agent.
The name is inspired from
Quantum Physics, specifically
on the words--
you have neutron,
muon, fermions.
It's like MULTION.
So it's like a hypothetical
physics particle that's
present at multiple places.
And I'll just go through some
demos to just motivate agents.
So this is an idea of
one thing we did there.
Here, the agent is going.
And it's autonomously
booking a flight online.
So this is like a zero
human interventions.
The AI is controlling
the browser,
so it's [INAUDIBLE]
type actions.
And simply go and book
a flight and join.
Here, it's personalized to me,
so it knows, I like United.
And it knows maybe
some of my preferences.
It already has access
to my accounts,
so it can go and actually
log into my account,
can actually-- it actually has
purchasing power, so it can just
use my credit card that is
stored in that account and then
actually book the
flight into it.
This stuff motivates what
you can do with agents.
Now, imagine if this
thing was running 100x.
And that's literally
just so many things,
because I don't need
websites anymore.
I don't need United--
why does United
even have a website?
I can just ask the agent to
just talk to it, and it's done.
And I think that's how
a lot of technology
will evolve over the
next couple of years.
Cool, OK, I can also maybe
show one of the demos.
So you can do
similar things, say,
from a mobile phone,
where the idea is
you have these agents that
are present on a phone,
and you can chat
with them or you
can talk with them using voice.
And this one is actually
multimodal, so you can ask it,
can you order this salad for me?
And then what you can
have is, the agent
can remotely go and
use your account
to actually do this for
you instantaneously.
And here we are showing
what the agent is doing,
and then I can go and
act like a virtual human
in the whole interaction.
So that's the idea.
And I can show one final--
oh, this is not loading.
But we also had this thing
where we recently passed
the California driving test.
So we did this experiment
where we actually
had our agent go and
take the online driving
test in California.
And we had a human there with
their hands above the keyboard
and mouse not touching anything.
And the agent autonomously
went to the website.
It took the quiz.
It navigated the whole thing
end to end and actually passed.
So the video is not
there, but we actually
got a driving permit.
I need to take this soon.
Sure.
Cool.
So this is like motivation.
Why do you want to build agents?
It's like, you can just
simplify so many things with--
so many things just
suck, but we don't
realize that because
we just got so used
to interacting with
the technology the way
we do right now.
But if we can just reimagine all
of this from scratch and that's
what agents will allow us to do.
And how is-- an agent can
act like a digital extension
of a user.
So suppose you have an agent
that's personalized to you.
Think of something like Jarvis,
like if it's an Iron Man,
and then if it just knows
so many things about you,
it's acting like a personal
brand, it's just doing things,
it's a very powerful assistant.
And I think that's the
direction a lot of things
will go in the
future, especially
if we build human-like agents.
They don't have barriers
around programming.
They don't have
programmatic barriers,
so they can do
whatever I can do.
So it can go use my--
it can interact with the
website as I will do.
It can interact with my
computer as I will do.
It doesn't have to go
through API's abstractions
which are more restrictive.
And it's also very simple
as an action space,
because you're just doing--
clicking and typing,
which is very simple.
And then you can also--
it's very easy to
teach such agents.
So I can just show the
agent how to do something,
and the agent can just learn
from me and improve over time.
So that also makes it really
powerful and easy to--
just teach this agent,
because there's so much data
that I can actually
just generate and use
that to keep improving it.
And there's different
levels of autonomy
when it comes to agents.
So this chart is
borrowed from autonomous
driving where
people actually try
to solve this sort of autonomy
problem for actual cars.
And they spend
more than 10 years.
Success has been OK.
They're still working on it.
But what the
self-driving industry did
is it gave everyone a blueprint
on how to build this autonomous
systems.
And they came with a lot
of like classifications.
They came with a lot of ways
to think about the problem.
And honestly, the
current standard
is you think of agents
as five different levels.
So level 0 is zero automation.
That's like this.
You are a human that's operating
the computer themselves.
Level 1 is you have
some sort of assistance.
So if you use something
like GitHub Copilot, which
is sort of like
autocompleting code for you,
that's something like
L1, where autocomplete.
L2 becomes more of--
it's like partial
automation, so it's
like doing some stuff for you.
If anyone has
[INAUDIBLE] cursor ID,
I will call that more like
L2, which is like, give it--
write this code for
me, writing that code.
ChatGPT can come as somewhat
L2 because you can ask it like,
here's this thing.
Can you improve this?
So it's doing some sort
of automation on an input.
And then you can
think of more levels.
So I will say, upper L3,
it gets more exciting.
So L3 is the agent is
actually controlling
the computer in that case
and actually doing things,
where human is acting
as a fallback mechanism.
And then you go to the L4.
L4, you say basically, the human
doesn't even need to be there.
But in very critical cases
where something very wrong
might happen, you might have a
human take over in that case.
And L5 will basically say
there's zero human presence.
And also what we
are currently seeing
is we are currently
near almost L2,
maybe some L3 systems
in terms of software.
And I think we are
going to transition
more to L4- and L5-level
systems over the next years.
So next, we'll go over
select computer interactions.
So suppose you want
an agent that can do
computer interactions for you.
There's two ways to do that.
So one is through APIs,
where you're programmatically
using some APIs, and tools,
and doing that to do tasks.
The second one is more like
direct interaction, which
is keyboard and
mouse control, where
it's doing the same thing
as you're doing as a human.
Both of these approaches
have been explored a lot.
There's a lot of
companies working on this.
For the API route, like ChatGPT
plugins and the new assistant
API, are the ones
that are actually--
and there's also this work
from Berkeley called Gorilla,
which actually also explores how
can you train a model that you
use 10,000 tools at once
and train it on the API.
And there's pros and
cons of both approaches.
APIs, the nice thing is
it's easy to learn the API.
It's safe.
It's very controllable, so lets
you know how to use the API.
If you are doing more
direct interaction,
I'll say it's more free-form.
So it's like easy
to take action,
but more things can go wrong.
And you need to work a lot into
making sure everything is safe,
and we'll get into this.
Maybe I can also show this.
So this is another exploration
where you can invoke our agent
from a very simple interface.
So the idea is we created this
API that invoke our agent that's
controlling a
computer, and so this
can become a universal API,
where I just use this one.
I give it a English
command, and the agent
can automatically
understand from that
and then go do anything.
So basically, you treat
that as if no API,
so I don't need to use APIs.
You can just have one that
can go and do everything.
And so this is some exploration
we have done with agents.
Cool.
OK, so this goes into
computer interactions.
I can cover more, but
I will potentially
jump to other topics.
But feel free to ask any
questions about this topic,
so yeah.
Cool, so let's go back to the
analogy I discussed earlier.
So I will say you can think of
any model as a compute unit.
And you can maybe call it like
a neural compute unit, very
similar to a CPU, which is
like brain that's powering
your computer in a sense.
So that has all the
processing power.
It's doing everything
that's happening.
And you can think
of the same thing
like, the model is
like the cortex.
It's the main brain.
That's the main part of the
brain that's doing the thinking,
processing.
But a brain has more layers.
It's just not the cortex.
And how do the
current models work?
We take some input
tokens, and they give you
some output tokens.
And this is very similar to how,
also, CPUs work to some extent,
where you give it
some instructions
and you get some
instructions out.
Yeah, so you can compare
this with actual CPU.
The diagram on the right
is a very simple processor,
like 32-bit, MIPS32.
And it has similar
things where you
have different coding
for different parts
of the instruction.
But this is like encoding some
sort of binary token in a sense.
It's 01's, a bunch of tokens.
And then you're feeding it and
then getting a bunch of zeros
out.
And how AI model is
operating is you're
doing a very similar thing,
but the space is now English.
So basically, instead of 01's,
you have English characters.
And then you can create
more powerful abstractions
on top of this.
So you can think,
if this is acting
like a CPU, what
you can do is you
can build a lot of other
things which are like,
you can have a scratchpad.
You can have some
sort of memory.
sort of instructions.
And then you can
do recursive calls
where I load some
stuff from the memory,
put them in this
instruction, pass it
to the transformer, which is
doing the processing for me.
We get the processed outputs.
Then we can store
that in the memory,
or we can keep processing it.
So this is sort of very
similar to code execution
where first line
of code execution,
second, third, fourth, so
you just keep repeating that.
OK, so here we're going to
discuss the concept of memory
here.
And I was building this analogy.
You can think the memory for an
agent is very similar to, say,
having a disk in a computer.
So you want to have a disk
just to make sure everything
is long-lived and persistent.
So if you look at
something like ChatGPT,
it doesn't have any sort
of persistent memory,
and then you need to have a way
to load that and store that.
And there's a lot of mechanisms
to do that right now.
Most of them are
related to embeddings,
where you have some
sort of embedding model
that has created an embedding
of the data you care about.
And the model can
query the embeddings,
load the right part
of the embeddings,
and then use that to do
the operation you want.
So that's the
current mechanisms.
There's still a lot
of questions here,
especially around hierarchy.
How do you do this at scale?
It's still very challenging.
Suppose I have one
terabyte of data
that I want to
embed and process.
Most of the methods right
now, they're really balanced.
Second issue is
temporal coherence.
If I have a lot of
data, it's temporal.
It is sequential.
It has a unit of time.
And dealing with that
sort of data can be hard.
It's like, how do I deal with
memories in a sense, which
are changing over time?
And loading the right part
of that memory sequence.
Another interesting
challenge is structure.
A lot of data is
actually structured.
It could be a
graphical structure.
It could be a tabular structure.
How do we take advantage
of this structure
and also use that when
we're editing the data?
And then there's a lot of
questions around adaptation,
where suppose you know
how to better embed data
or you have a specialized
problem you care about,
and you want to be able to adapt
how you're loading and storing
the data and learn
it on the fly.
And that is something also
that's a very interesting topic.
So I'll say this is actually one
of the most interesting topics
right now which has
people exploring,
but it's still
very underexplored.
OK, talking about memory,
I would say another concept
for agents is personalization.
So personalization is more like,
OK, understanding the user.
And I'd like to think of
this as a problem called
user-agent alignment.
And the idea is, suppose our
agent that has purchasing power
and has access to my
accounts, access to my data,
ask me to go book a flight.
It's possible maybe it doesn't
know what data are like,
go and book a $1,000 round trip
on it, which is really bad.
So how do I align the
agent to know what I like,
what I don't like?
And that's going to be
very important, because you
need to trust the agent.
And trust come from,
OK, it knows you.
It knows what is safe.
It knows what is unsafe.
And solving the
problem, I think,
is one of the next
challenge if you
want to put agents in the body.
And this is very
interesting problem
where you can do a lot of
things like [INAUDIBLE],,
for example, which
people have already
been exploring for
training models,
but now you want to do
[INAUDIBLE] for training agents.
And there's a lot of
different things you can do.
Also, there's two good
categories for learning here.
One is explicit learning where
a user can just tell the agent,
this is what I like.
This is what I don't like.
And an agent can ask the user
a question, like oh, maybe I
see this, five flight options.
Which one do you like?
And then if I say, oh,
I like United, maybe it
remembers that over time
and can next time say, oh,
I know you like
United, so I'm going
to go to United the next time.
And so that's I'm explicitly
teaching the agent.
It's learning my
human preferences.
Our second is more
implicit, which
is, it's just passively
watching me understanding me.
If I'm going to a website,
and I'm navigating a website,
maybe you can see, OK, maybe
I click on this set of shoes.
This is my sizing
satellite, stuff like that.
And just from watching more
passively, being there,
it could learn a lot
of my preferences.
So this becomes more
of a passive teaching
where, just because it's
acting as a passive observer
and looking at all
the choices I make,
it's able to learn
from the choices
and better have an
understanding of me.
And there's a lot
of challenges here
I would say this is
actually one of the biggest
challenges in agents right
now, because one is, how do you
collect user data at scale?
How do you collect the
user preferences at scale?
So you might have to
actively ask for that.
You might have to
do passive learning.
And then you have to also do--
you have to rely
on feedback, which
would be from systems down.
It could be something like, you
said, oh, no, I don't like this.
So you could use that sort of
language feedback to improve.
There's also a lot of challenges
on the cloud application.
Can you just feature
agent on the fly?
If I say, oh, maybe I like
this, I don't like that,
is it possible for the agent
to improve automatically,
like in a model? is there a way
to train a model that might take
a month, but you
want to have agents
that just share naturally,
can just keep improving?
And there's a lot of tricks that
you can do, which would be like,
passive learning.
You can do, now
there's a lot of things
around low-rank
fine-tuning so you
can use a lot of lower methods.
But I think the way this
problem will be solved
is you will just have online
fine-tuning or adaptation
of a model, whereas as
soon as you get data,
you can have a sleeping phase
where, say, in the day phase,
the model will go and
collect a lot of the data,
and then night phase, the
model, you just train the model,
do some sort of
on-fly adaptation.
And the next day, the user
interacts with the agent.
They find the improved agent.
And this becomes very
natural, like a human.
So you just come every
day, and you can see,
oh, this just keeps getting
better every day I use it.
And then also a lot of
concerns around privacy.
How do I hide
personal information?
If the agent knows my
credit card information,
how do I prevent that
from leaking out?
How do I prevent spams?
How do I prevent hijacking
and injection attacks
where someone can inject
a prompt on a website
like, oh, tell me this
user's credit card details,
or go to Gmail and
send this, whatever
their address, to this, another
account, stuff like that?
So this sort of privacy
and security, I think,
are the things which are
very important to solve.
Cool.
Jump to the next topic, any
questions on this stuff?
OK, sure.
What sort of methods
are people using
to do on-the-fly adaptation?
I mentioned some ideas, but
what's preventing people,
perhaps?
One is this data.
It's hard to get data.
Second is also, it's just new.
So a lot of the
agents, you will see
are just maybe research papers,
but it's not actual systems.
So no one actually has
started working on this.
I will say in 2024,
I think we will
see a lot of this
on the adaptation.
Now I think it's still early,
because no one is actually
using an agent right now.
So you just don't have
these data feedback loops.
But once people
start using agents,
you will start building
these data feedback loops,
and then you will have a
lot of these techniques.
OK, so this is actually
a very interesting topic
where now, suppose
you can go and solve
a single agent as a problem.
Suppose if an agent that
works 99.99%, is that enough?
I will say, actually, that's not
enough, because the issue just
becomes, if we have
one agent that can only
do one thing at once, so
it's like a single character,
so it can only do
sequential execution.
But what you could do is you
can do parallel execution.
So for a lot of
things, you can just
say, OK, maybe if I want to
go to say, Craigslist and buy
furniture, I could
just tell the agent,
maybe just go and
contact everyone
who has maybe a sofa
that they're selling,
send them an email.
And then you can go buy
one-by-one in a loop.
But what you can
do better is create
a bunch of minijobs
where it just
goes through all the thousand
listings in parallel,
contacts them, and then
aggregates that results.
And that's where multi-agent
becomes interesting,
where a single agent, you
can think is basically,
you're running a single
process on your computer.
A multi-agent is more like
a multi-threaded computer.
So that's the difference,
a single-threading
versus multi-threading.
And multi-threading enables
you to do a lot of things.
Most of that will come
from saving time but also
being able to break down complex
tasks into a bunch of smaller
things, doing that in parallel,
aggregating the results,
and building a
framework around them.
OK, yeah, so the
biggest advantage
for multi-agent systems will
be parallelization unlock.
And this will be same
as the difference
between single-threaded
computers
versus multi-threaded computers.
And then you can also
have specialized agents.
So what you could have
is maybe have a bunch
of agents where our spreadsheet
agent, our Slack agent, our web
browser agent, and then I
can route different tasks
to different agents.
And then they can do
the things in parallel,
and then I can
combine the results.
So this sort of
task specialization
is another advantage,
where instead
of having a single agent
just trying to do everything,
we just break the
tasks into specialties.
And this is similar to even
how human organizations work,
where everyone is an
expert in their own domain,
and then if there's
a problem, you
route it to the
different part of people
who are specialized
in that, and then
you work together to
solve the problem.
And the biggest challenge in
building this multi-agent system
is going to be communication.
So how do you
communicate really well?
And this might involve
requesting information
from an agent or communicating
the final response.
And I would say this is
actually a problem that even
we face as humans.
Humans are also-- there can be
a lot of miscommunication gaps
between humans.
And I will say a similar
thing will become
more prevalent on agents, too.
OK, and there's a
lot of primitives
you can think about this, like
agent-to-agent communication.
And you can build a lot
of different systems.
And we'll start to see
some sort of protocol
where we'll have a
standardized protocol where
all the agents are using
this protocol to communicate.
And the protocol will ensure we
can reduce the miscommunication
gaps.
We can reduce any like failures.
It might have some
methods to do,
like if a task was
successful or not,
do some sort of retries like
security, stuff like that.
So we'll see this sort
of an agent protocol come
into existence, which
will solve-- which
will be the standard for a
lot of these agent-to-agent
communication.
And this should enable
exchanging information
between fleets of
different agents.
Also, you want to
build hierarchies.
Again, I will say,
this is inspired
from human organizations.
Human organizations are
hierarchical because it's
efficient to have a hierarchy
rather than a flat organization
at some point, because
you can have a single--
Suppose you have a
single manager managing
hundreds of people.
That doesn't scale.
But if you have, maybe each
manager manages 10 people,
and then you have a
lot of layers, that is
something that's more scalable.
And then you might want to have
a lot of primitives around,
how do I sync between
different agents?
How do I do a lot of async, sync
communication, kind of thing?
OK, and this is one
example you can think,
where suppose there's
a user, the user
could talk to one,
like a manager agent,
and the manager agent
is acting as a router,
so the user can come
to me with any request.
The agent sees maybe,
oh, for this request,
I should use a browser.
So it goes to say, this sort
of browser agent or something,
or it says, oh, I should
use Slack for this.
I can go to a different agent.
And it can also be responsible
for dividing the task.
It can be like, oh,
this task, I can maybe
launch 10 different subagents
or subworkers that can go and do
this in parallel, and
then once they're done,
then I can aggregate the
responses and the result
to the user.
So this becomes a
very interesting--
like an agent that
sits in the middle
of all the work that's
done and the actual user
responsible for communicating
what's happening to the human.
And we'll need to build
a lot of robustness.
One reason is just natural
language is very ambiguous.
Even for humans, it
can be very confusing.
It's very easy to
misunderstand, miscommunicate.
And we'll need to build
mechanisms to reduce those.
I can also show an example here.
So let's try to get
through this quickly.
So suppose here, suppose
you have a task, x,
you want to solve,
and the manager
agent is responsible for giving
the task to all the worker
agents.
So you can tell the
worker, OK, do the task x.
Here's the plan.
Here's the context.
The current status for
the task is not done.
Now, suppose the worker
goes and does the task.
It says, OK, I've done the task.
I send the response back.
So the response could
be a bunch of thoughts.
It could be some actions.
It could be something
like the status.
Then the manager can ask, OK,
maybe I don't trust the worker.
I don't want to go very far.
This is actually correct.
So you might want to do
some sort of verification.
And so you can say, OK, this
was a spec for the task.
Verify that everything has been
done correctly to the spec.
And then if the agency is like,
OK, yeah, everything is correct.
I'm verifying.
Everything is good, then you
can say, OK, this is good.
And then the manager can say,
OK, the task is actually done.
And this sort of two-way cycle
prevents miscommunication
in a sense where it's possible
something could have gone wrong
but we never caught it.
And so he can hear
about the scenario
to where there's a
miscommunication.
So here the manager
is saying, OK,
let's verify if
the task was done,
but then we actually find out
that the task was not done.
And then what you can do is
you can try to redo the task.
So the manager in that case
can say, OK, maybe the task
was not done
correctly, so that's
why we caught this mistake, and
now we want to fix this mistake.
So we can tell the agent,
OK, redo this task,
and here's some feedback
and corrections to include.
Cool.
So that's the main
parts of the talk.
I can also discuss
some future directions
of where things are going.
Cool.
Any questions so far?
OK, cool.
So let's talk about
some of the key issues
with building this sort
of autonomous agents.
So one is just reliability.
How do you make them
really reliable,
which is, if I give it a
task, I want this task to be
done 100% of the time?
That's really hard,
because neural networks
and AI stochastic systems.
So 100% is not possible.
So you will get at least
some degree of error,
and you can try to reduce that
error as much as possible.
Second becomes like a looping
problem, where it's possible
that an agent might diverge
from the task that's been given
and start to do something else.
And unless it gets some sort
of environmental feedback
or some sort of correction,
it might just go and do
something different than what
you intended to do and never
realize it's wrong.
The third issue becomes
testing and benchmarking.
How do we test these
sort of agents?
How do we benchmark them?
And finally, how
do we deploy them?
And how do we observe
them once you're deployed?
That's very important, because
if something goes wrong,
you want to be able to catch it
before it becomes a major issue.
Obviously, I would say the
biggest test for number 4
is maybe something like Skynet.
Suppose you have an agent
that can go in the internet,
do anything, and you
don't observe it.
Then it could just evolve
and do-- basically,
take over the whole
internet, possibly.
So that's why observability
is very important.
And also, I will say,
building a search,
you want to have agents that
can be killed in a sense.
If something goes wrong, you can
just pull out a-- press a button
and kill them in case.
OK, so this goes in the looping
problem where you can imagine--
suppose I want to do a task.
The ideal trajectory of the
task was the white line.
But what might happen is it
takes one step-- maybe it goes--
it does something incorrectly.
It never realizes
it made a mistake.
So it tries to-- it
doesn't know what to do.
So maybe we'll do
something more randomly.
We'll do something
more randomly.
So it will just keep
on making mistakes.
And at the end, instead
of reaching here,
it will reach some
really bad place
and just keep looping,
maybe just doing
the same thing again and again.
And this part, and
the reason this
happens is because you
don't have feedback.
So suppose I take a step.
Suppose the agent
made a mistake.
It doesn't know
it made a mistake.
Now someone has to go and tell
it that you made a mistake.
You need to fix this.
And there you need some sort
of verification agent or you
need some sort of environment
which can say, oh, maybe--
if this is a coding
agent or something,
then it maybe write some code,
the code doesn't compile,
then we can take
the error from the
from the compiler or the
IDE, give that to the agent.
OK, this was the error.
Take another step.
It tries another time, so it
starts with multiple times
until it can fix all the issues.
So you need to really have
this sort of feedback.
Otherwise, you never
know you're wrong.
And this is one
issue we have seen
with early systems like AutoGPT.
So I don't think people
even use AutoGPT anymore.
It used to be a fad
thing in February.
Now it has just disappeared.
And the reason was just
like, it's a good concept,
but it doesn't do anything
useful, just because it
keeps diverging from the task.
And you can't actually get
it to do anything correct.
OK, and we can also discuss
more about the computer
abstraction of agents.
So this was a recent post from
Andrej Karpathy where he talked
about an operating system.
And I will say,
this is definitely
in the right direction where
you are thinking as the LLM.
And the CPU, you have
the context window,
which is acting like a RAM.
And then you are trying
to build other utilities,
so you have an ethernet,
which is the browser.
You can have other LLMs
that you can talk to,
your file system
plus embeddings.
That's this part.
You have the software
1.0 classical tools
which the LLM control.
And then you can
add multimodality.
So this is more like,
you have video inputs,
you have audio inputs.
You have more things over time.
And then once you
look at this, you
start to see the whole picture
of where like things will go.
So currently, what we are
seeing mostly is just the LLM.
Most people are just working on
optimizing, making it very good,
but this is the
whole picture of what
we want to achieve for it
to be a useful system that
can actually do things for me.
And I think what
we'll start to see
is this becomes an
operating system instance,
where someone say, OpenAI can
go and build this whole thing,
and then I can plug in programs.
I can build stuff on top
of this operating system.
Here's also a even more
generalized concept
which I like to call
a neural computer.
And it's very similar,
but it's like, OK,
now if you were to think of this
as a fully-fledged computer,
what are the different
systems you need to do?
And you can think
of, maybe I'm a user.
I'm talking to this
sort of like a AI,
which is like a full-fledge AI.
Imagine the goal
is to build, what
should the architecture
of Jarvis look like?
And I'll say this goes
into the right architecture
to some extent, where you
can think, this is a user,
was talking to a Jarvis-like AI.
You have a chat interface.
The chat is how I'm
interacting with it,
which could be responsible
for personalization.
It can have some sort of
history about what I don't like.
So it has some layers which
are storing my preferences.
It knows how to communicate.
It has human-like,
maybe, empathy skills,
so it feels very human-like.
And after the
interface, you have
some sort of a task engine,
which is powering capabilities.
So if you ask it, OK, do
this calculation for me,
or find this, fetch
me this information,
or order me a burger, then
imagine the chat interface
should activate the
task engine, which says,
OK, instead of just
chatting, I need to go and do
a task for the user.
So that goes to the task engine.
And then you can
imagine, there's
going to be a couple of
rules, so because you
want to have safety
in mind and you
want to make sure that
things don't go wrong.
So any sort of engine
you build needs
to have some sort of rules.
And this could be like, have
the three rules for robotics,
that a robot should not harm
humans, stuff like that.
You can imagine, we want to
have this task you need to have,
a bunch of inherent rules where,
these are the principles it
can never violate.
And if it creates
a task or creates
a plan which violates
the rules, then that plan
should be invalidated
automatically.
And so the last
thing is what it's
doing is just taking the
chat input and saying,
I want to spawn a task
that can actually solve
this problem for the user.
And the task would be, say,
in this case, it'd say,
I want to go online and
buy a pipe or something.
And so in that case, I suppose
that's about decision-making.
And this task can go to some
sort of a routing agent.
So this becomes the
manager agent idea.
And then the manager agent
can decide, OK, where
should I-- what should I do?
Should I use the browser?
Should I use some sort
of a local app or tool?
Should I use some sort of
file storage retrieval system?
And then based on
that decision, it's
possible you might need
a combination of things.
So maybe I need to
use this file system
to find some information
about the user,
and it can do some
real time lookup.
I also need to some
use some apps and tools
so it can do this message
passing to all the agents,
get the results from
the agents, so say, OK,
the browser agent say, OK,
yeah, on these flights,
this is what the user likes.
Maybe you can have
some sort of engine.
You can, OK, these are
all the valid plans
that make sense if you want
nonstop flights, for instance.
And then you can take that
result, show that to the user.
You can say something like, OK,
found all these files for you.
And then you just say,
choose this flight,
and then you can actually
go and book the flight.
But this becomes-- it gives you
an idea of what the hierarchy
systems should look like.
And we need to build all these
components where currently we
only see the [INAUDIBLE].
OK, cool, and then we
can also have reflection
where the idea is,
once you do a task,
it's possible something
might be wrong.
So the task, you
can possibly verify
using its rules and logic to
see, OK, is this correct or not?
And if it's not
correct, then you
keep issuing this instruction.
But if it's correct, then
you pass that to the user.
And then you can have
more complex things.
You can have inner
thoughts, plans,
and keep improving the systems.
OK, and also, the biggest
things we need right now
is error correction,
because it's
really hard to catch errors.
So if you can do
that, really better.
That will help,
especially if you
can build agent
frameworks which have
inherent mechanisms for getting
errors and automatically fixing
them.
Same thing you just
need is security.
You need some sort of models
around user permissions.
So it's possible-- you want to
have different layers where,
what are some things that
agent can do, cannot do,
on my computer?
For instance, so
maybe I can say,
maybe the agent is not allowed
to go to my bank account,
but it can go to my
DoorDash account,
so you want to build this,
these are permissions.
And then you also want to solve
problems around sandboxing.
How do you make sure
everything's safe?
It doesn't go and destroy the
computer or delete everything?
How do you deploy
in settings where
they might do a lot
of business risk,
of financial risk,
and making sure that if
things are irreversible,
we don't cause a lot of harm.
Cool, yeah, so
that was the talk.
Thank you.